<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kungsleden 2021 on Richard Strnad</title>
    <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kungsleden 2021 on Richard Strnad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 14 - Sáltoluokta</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day14/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 5:31
KM: 23.21
Elevation gain in Meters: 340
Start: Under Mártevárásj
End: Sáltoluokta
Morning I woke up around 6 am as it was too hot in the tent. After removing the rainfly partially it got a bit better. But on the way back into the tent, around 10 mosquitoes followed me… so it was hunting time again. Unbelievable that they are now on the fjäll as well, we really hope it gets better in the next 1-2 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 13 - Skierffe</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day13/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 8:08
KM: 26.82
Elevation gain in Meters: 1008
Start: Fjäll after Jågge shelter
End: Under Mártevárásj
Down again The night was on the warm side but we slept perfectly! Especially after the mosquito infested hostel room…
  Tent on the fjäll
  First target of the day was to reach boat station. Schedule of the motorboat was 9 am and 5 pm but there was also a rowing option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 12 - Out of Kvikkjokk</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day12/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 8:18
KM: 28.82
Elevation gain in Meters: 937
Start: Kvikkjokk
End: Fjäll after Jågge shelter
Back on the trail After not the best night thanks to the mosquitoes I got up at 7 am and decided to get breakfast. Nicole slept for another hour :) Even though we hadn’t booked breakfast, I was able to get one (but without eggs) and it was a great start into the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 11 - Nero Town Day</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day11/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 1:35
KM: 6:05
Elevation gain in Meters: 33
Start: Near Lástak on the trail
End: Kvikkjokk
Good morning We slept good and got up around 7 am, it was warm more or less the whole night. But in the morning the mosquitoes were still attached to our tent, so putting it down was bit of a challenge.
  Mosquito infested tent
  Way down We hit the trail shortly before 8 am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 10 - Getting close to Kvikkjokk</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day10/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 9:53
KM: 35.36
Elevation gain in Meters: 969
Start: Fjäll near Tjäurakåtan
End: Near Lástak on the trail
Windy night Thankfully we and the tent survived the windy night :) Early morning the wind stopped completely. For part of the night I listed to music again to kill the noises from the wind, that works quite good.
In the morning we got a beautiful view out of the tent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 9 - First real boat ride</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day9/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 7:47
KM: 27.08
Elevation gain in Meters: 811
Start: Top of the Fjäll before the boatride to Vuonatjviken
End: Fjäll near Tjäurakåtan
Boatride There was a bit wind before we went to bed, but not an issue compared to the night before. We both slept pretty good, the swim/shower in the lake helped with that i guess :)
  View of the camp in the morning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 8 - Windy night</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day8/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 6:31
KM: 21.83
Elevation gain in Meters: 617
Start: After Pieljekaisestugan
End: Top of the Fjäll before the boatride to Vuonatjviken
Waking up from the wind I had a bit of a hard time to fall asleep because of the wind. Because it hit the tent quite hard, there was a lot of noise inside of it… everyday another challenge ;-)
At around 1 am i woke up again and couldn’t fell asleep because of the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 7 - Next Town, Adolfsström</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day7/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 10:11
KM: 35.51
Elevation gain in Meters: 825
Start: Near Svájpavallie
End: After Pieljekaisestugan
Good Morning Yesterday shortly before I fell asleep, it started to rain. Not sure how long it continued, but in the morning it was mostly dry. ‌And the mosquitoes were gone! At least for the moment ;-)
  View from the tent spot
  It was quite cloudy, but the sun sometimes managed to push trough and spent some heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 6 - On the plateau</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day6/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 7:04
KM: 25.45
Elevation gain in Meters: 417
Start: Bridges after Rävfallstugan
End: Near Svájpavallie
Cold night The night was cold, the close river probably didn‘t helped with that… I had a really hard time to get out of the sleepingbag but as soon as the sunshine hit me, it was ok 😀
As we reached the plateau yesterday before we set camp, the trail was mostly flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 5 - Waking up in a bed</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day5/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 8:09
KM: 30.24
Elevation gain in Meters: 1160
Start: Ammarnäs
End: Bridges after Rävfallstugan
Waking up and Breakfast Even if we love our tent and camping in the wild, a real bed is amazing after some days outside. The same goes for a shower and a breakfast. We had all of it in Ammarnäs, but then it was time to hit the trail again.
During the night it rained lightly, but when we started around 10, it was still cloudy but dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 4 - First Town</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day4/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 5:21
KM: 19.15
Elevation gain in Meters: 405
Start: After Vuomatjåhkka shelter
End: Ammarnäs
Next stop Ammarnäs We slept well, I woke up once and it sounded like light rain but in the morning it was cloudy but not raining. First goal of the day was the emergency shelter on top of the next pass. It took us an hour for 3.6km and 270m of elevation gain. We then had breakfast in the shelter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 3 - From the water back to the mountains</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day3/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 8:11
KM: 27.4
Elevation gain in Meters: 934
Start: Before Tärnasjöstugorna‌
End: After Vuomatjåhkka shelter
Warm start After a cozy night we woke up and the sun was still shining and no clouds in sight. That was a pleasant surprise. Then sun was warming us up and this helped to get started.
The first kms followed along the lake, through the forest.
  Forest Hiking along Tärnasjön</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 2 - Cold night, beautiful day</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day2/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 7:24
KM: 22.8
Elevation gain in Meters: 439
Start: Shortly after Viterskalsstugan‌
End: Before Tärnasjöstugorna
Start of day 2 Day 2 started for me at 3am, as i had to pee. It‘s crazy to get up this early and realize that it‘s bright as during the day.
  3am in the morning
  Overall we slept pretty good, it was on the cold side but tolerable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 1 - The start (is always hard?)</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/day1/</guid>
      <description>Overview Hiking duration: 3:53
KM: 12.08
Elevation gain in Meters: 528
Start: Hemavan
End: Shortly after Viterskalsstugan
Before the start After we arrived by plane we repacked our stuff directly in front of the mini airport building. Then we went off to get food for the next ~4 days which it will take to reach Ammarnäs. The local ICA had a nice selection of food.
Then we went for a final meal before the start at the „Auroras kök“ and we both choose the Beyond Burger (Vegetarian).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden Day 0 - Travel, getting to the start</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/travel/</guid>
      <description>Overview KM: 0 by foot
Start: Rheinfelden
End: Hemavan
Train, Plane, Hotel and Plane again Getting to the start of the Kungsleden is quite a journey, at least when you live in switzerland or Rheinfelden to be more specific. There are various options, but we decided to go by plane in the end. As there are no direct (or even combined) flights available, we had to split the journey. So the first flight was Zurich -&amp;gt; Stockholm and as there was no flight which allowed us to capture the next flight to Hemavan on the same day, we went for a Hotel in Stockholm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden T -1 days - Finalizing the equipment</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/equipment-finalizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/equipment-finalizing/</guid>
      <description>Equipment for the Kungsleden For this year i wanted to put everything into a lighterpack and i really did it 🥳 This is mostly for myself and should help me in the future to optimize the weight.
Lighterpack Base weight could definitely be better and we are considering a ZPacks triplex for the future. But this is a topic for another day.
How does all this stuff look like? I captured two pictures of my equipment, one shows most of the stuff just loose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kungsleden T -4 days</title>
      <link>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardstrnad.github.io/hikes/kungsleden-2021/overview/</guid>
      <description>After we really enjoyed our nearly 3 week (20 days) hike on the via Alpina in 2020, we decided to go for another thruhike in 2021. There where multiple options in Switzerland which we considered but in the end we decided for Sweden and the Kungsleden.
Now 4 days before we leave for Stockholm, as first stop in our Journey, the final preparation is going on :)
More to follow soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
